A Finding Aid to the Albert Kahn Papers, 1875-1970, bulk 1875-1945, in the Archives of American Art AAA.kahnalbp
Archives of American Art
Albert Kahn papers
1875-1970
AAA.kahnalbp
Archives of American Art
6.5 Linear feet
The papers of architect Albert Kahn date from 1875-1970, bulk 1875-1945, and measure 6.5 linear feet. Found within the papers is biographical material, correspondence, personal business records, nine sketchbooks, art work, notes and writings, two scrapbooks, printed material, photographs and photograph albums, artifacts, and motion picture film.
Kahn, Albert
Provenance
The Albert Kahn papers were donated by Kahn's children, Mrs. Lydia Winston Malbin, Mrs. Rosalie Butzel, and Dr. Edgar A. Kahn, in 1974.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment. Use of archival audiovisual recordings with no duplicate access copy requires advance notice. Glass plate negative is house separately and closed to researchers.
Biographical Note
Albert Kahn (1869-1942) of Detroit, Michigan, was an architect, primarily known for designing industrial buildings with the pioneering use of reinforced concrete that allowed large unobstructed interiors.
Albert Kahn was born on March 21, 1869 in Rhaunen, Rhineland-Palatinate, Germany, the oldest son of rabbi Joseph Kahn and Rosalie Cohn Kahn. The family immigrated to the United States in 1881 and settled in Detroit, Michigan.
Albert Kahn worked as an office boy in an architect's office and studied drawing in Sunday classes conducted by sculptor Julius Melchers. Melchers found Kahn a position in the architectural offices of Mason and Rice where he worked for several years. In 1890, Kahn won a scholarship to travel in Europe to study architecture and in 1895 he opened his own architectural office, Albert Kahn Associates, hiring his younger brothers, Louis, Moritz, and Felix. In the following year, Kahn married Ernestine Krolik.
In 1903, Kahn was awarded his first two important commissions: to design the University of Michigan's engineering building and the Palm Apartments in Detroit, built with the early use of reinforced concrete. In the following year, he built the first reinforced concrete factory for the Packard Motor Company. Because of the industrial growth in Detroit at that time, Kahn was in demand to design various automobile factories including the General Motors Building, textile, business machine, and chemical plants. He became an authority on concrete construction and by the beginning of the First World War, his firm provided construction for the military aviation section of the Army.
Kahn later moved from using concrete to steel and glass. In 1927, his company finished a large building for the Fisher Brothers of Detroit for which he was awarded a medal by the Architectural League of New York for the year's outstanding contribution to architecture. In the following year his firm was given full charge of the entire heavy industrial building program of Russia's first five-year plan, and they constructed an estimated two billion dollars worth of factories in Russia.
During World War II, Kahn's firm was constantly busy constructing naval air bases, airplane engine plants, tank arsenals including the Detroit Arsenal Tank Plant, and other government defense projects. In June 1942 Kahn was given the honorary degree of Doctor of Fine Arts by Syracuse University.
Albert Kahn died on December 8, 1942 in Detroit, Michigan.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of architect Albert Kahn date from 1875-1970, bulk 1875-1945, and measure 6.5 linear feet. Found within the papers are biographical material, correspondence, personal business records, nine sketchbooks, art work, notes and writings, two scrapbooks, printed material, photographs and photograph albums, artifacts, a sound recording and motion picture film.
Biographical material includes a biographical account, marriage certificate, architect's licenses, calling cards for the Kahns, passports, identification cards, letters of introduction, award certificates and medals, membership cards and certificates, a sound recording concerning Albert Kahn's life, and an address book.
Correspondence consists of letters between Albert Kahn, family members, and colleagues including Myron Barlow, George D. Mason, Carl Milles and Arthur A. Stoughton. There is one letter each from Henry Bacon and Alexander Trowbridge, and condolence letters to Kahn's widow.
Personal business records include records of stocks and income, lists of expenses and receipts for construction, property records, price lists for paintings by others, and miscellaneous receipts.
Art work includes nine sketchbooks and drawings by Albert Kahn, a paper silhouette portrait of Kahn, and drawings, watercolors, etchings, lithographs, and a sketchbook of Cornwall by others.
Notes and writings include Ernestine Kahn's diary, notebooks, guest registers and records concerning Albert Kahn's funeral, and typescripts of speeches and lectures.
Two scrapbooks contain clippings, small drawings, photographs of architecture, and letters of tribute.
Printed material includes clippings, exhibition catalogs for others, programs, booklets, books, reproductions of art work, travel brochures, picture postcards, and miscellaneous printed material.
Photographs are of Albert Kahn, members of his family, and colleagues including Myron Barlow, Frida Kahlo, Diego Rivera, Arturo Toscanini, residences, and travel scenes. There are also five reels of 16mm motion picture film of the Kahn family at the farm and at various family gatherings.
Artifacts primarily consist of the tools used by Albert Kahn during his career including t-squares and portable tripod supports for drawing boards used on construction sites.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 9 series. Glass plate negative housed separately and closed to researchers.
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1896-1945 (Box 1, 6, OV 10; 19 folders)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1891-1970 (Box 1-3, 6; 3.3 linear feet)
Series 3: Personal Business Records, 1891-1943 (Box 3; 7 folders)
Series 4: Art Work, 1890-1936 (Box 3, 6, OV 11-12; 20 folders)
Series 5: Notes and Writings, 1899-1943 (Box 3-4; 29 folders)
Series 6: Scrapbooks, 1890-1942 (Box 7; 0.3 linear feet)
Series 7: Printed Material, 1897-1968 (Box 4-6, OV 10; 0.8 linear feet)
Series 8: Photographs, 1875-1944 (Box 5-6, 8, MGP 2; 1.0 linear feet)
Series 9: Artifacts, circa 1942 (Box 5, 9; 0.4 linear feet)
Bacon, Henry, 1839-1912; Barlow, Myron, 1873-1937; Kahlo, Frida; Kahn, Ernestine Krolik; Mason, George D.; Milles, Carl, 1875-1955; Rivera, Diego, 1886-1957; Stoughton, Arthur A.; Toscanini, Arturo, 1867-1957; Trowbridge, Alexander Buell, 1868-1950; Architects--Michigan--Detroit; Architecture, American; Awards; Diaries; Drawings; Etchings; Lectures; Lithographs; Motion pictures (visual works); Notebooks; Notes; Photographs; Renderings; Scrapbooks; Sketchbooks; Sound recordings; Typescripts; Watercolors
- Biographical Material, 1896-1945; Series 1; (Box 1, 6, OV 10; 19 folders)
  Scope and Contents note
  Biographical material includes a biographical account, marriage certificate, architect's licenses from several states, calling cards for Albert and Ernestine Kahn, passports, a driver's permit, identification cards, letters of introduction from Ralph H. Booth and W. R. Valentiner of the Detroit Institute of Arts, archeologist Francis Willey Kelsey, and the president of the Cadillac Motor Company, award certificates and medals, membership cards and certificates, a sound recording concerning Albert Kahn's life, and Ernestine Kahn's address book.
  - Biographical Account, 1942; (Oversized Material Housed in Box 6) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Calling Cards for Albert and Mrs. Kahn, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Passports, 1920-1925 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Driving Permit and Identification Cards, 1937-1942 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letters of Introduction, 1911-1930; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  - Award Certificates, 1926-1943; (3 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 6) (Box 1, Folder 7-9)
  - Award Medal from the Pittsburgh Glass Institution, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - File Concerning the Frank P. Brown Medal, 1943; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
  - Membership Certificates, 1930-1941, undated; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
  - Membership Cards, 1932-1943; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 15-16)
  - Sound Recording The Story of Albert Kahn, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Address Book of Mrs. Kahn, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Oversized Marriage Certificate, 1896; (from Box 1, Folder 1) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Three Oversized Architect's Licenses, 1921-1924 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Three Oversized Award Certificates, 1930-1937; (from Box 1, Folder 8) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Two Oversized Architect's Licenses, 1918-1923 (Box OV 10)
- Correspondence, 1891-1970; Series 2; (Box 1-3, 6; 3.3 linear feet)
  Correspondence includes letters between Albert Kahn and his wife concerning their courtship, marriage, and family life. Correspondence is also with various Kahn family members and colleagues including Myron Barlow, George D. Mason, Carl Milles, and Arthur A. Stoughton. There is one letter each from Henry Bacon and Alexander Trowbridge. Numerous condolence letters to Kahn's widow are from friends and colleagues including Paul Cret, Edsel Ford, Carl Milles, and Eliel Saarinen.
  - Between Albert Kahn and Ernestine Krolik Kahn, 1894; (12 folders) (Box 1, Folder 19-30)
  - Between Albert Kahn and Ernestine Krolik Kahn, 1895; (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 31-33)
  - Between Albert Kahn and Ernestine Krolik Kahn, 1896; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 34-35)
  - Between Albert Kahn and Ernestine Krolik Kahn, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Between Albert Kahn and Ernestine Krolik Kahn, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Between Albert Kahn and Ernestine Krolik Kahn, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Between Albert Kahn and Ernestine Krolik Kahn, 1931-1934 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Concerning the Wedding of Albert Kahn and Ernestine Krolik, 1896; (11 folders) (Box 1, Folder 40-50)
  - From Albert Kahn to his Wife and Children, 1907-1922, undated, (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 51-53)
  - Letters of Condolence, Surnames Unknown, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Letters of Condolence, Surnames "A,", 1942-1943; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 55-56)
  - Letters of Condolence, Surnames "B,", 1942-1943; (10 folders) (Box 1, Folder 57-66)
  - Letters of Condolence, Surnames "C,", 1942-1943; (5 folders) (Box 1, Folder 67-71)
  - Letters of Condolence, Surnames "D,", 1942-1943; (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 72-74)
  - Letters of Condolence, Surnames "E,", 1942-1943; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 75-76)
  - Letters of Condolence, Surnames "F,", 1942-1943; (4 folders) (Box 2, Folder 1-4)
  - Letters of Condolence, Surnames "G,", 1942-1943; (4 folders) (Box 2, Folder 5-8)
  - Letters of Condolence, Surnames "H,", 1942-1943; (6 folders) (Box 2, Folder 9-14)
  - Letters of Condolence, Surnames "I" - "J,", 1942-1943; (5 folders) (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Letters of Condolence, Surnames "K,", 1942-1943 (Box 2, Folder 16-20)
  - Letters of Condolence, Surnames "L,", 1942-1943; (4 folders) (Box 2, Folder 21-24)
  - Letters of Condolence, Surnames "M,", 1942-1943; (5 folders) (Box 2, Folder 25-29)
  - Letters of Condolence, Surnames "N,", 1942-1943 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Letters of Condolence, Surnames "O,", 1942-1943 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Letters of Condolence, Surnames "P,", 1942-1943; (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 32-33)
  - Letters of Condolence, Surnames "R,", 1942-1943; (4 folders) (Box 2, Folder 34-37)
  - Letters of Condolence, Surnames "S,", 1942-1943; (7 folders) (Box 2, Folder 38-44)
  - Letters of Condolence, Surnames "T,", 1942-1943; (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 45-46)
  - Letters of Condolence, Surnames "U" - "V,", 1942-1943 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Letters of Condolence, Surnames "W,", 1942-1943; (4 folders) (Box 2, Folder 48-51)
  - Letters of Condolence, Surnames "Y" - "Z,", 1942-1943 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Condolence Notes Accompanying Flowers, 1942; (4 folders) (Box 2, Folder 53-56)
  - Condolence Notes Accompanying Flowers, 1942; (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
  - Surnames Unknown, 1894-1942, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Atkins - Baldwin, 1900-1944 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Myron Barlow, 1907-1912 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Barnard - Butzel, 1897-1920 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Carse - Daman Fire Proofing Company, 1901-1964 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Detroit Historical Museum, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Detroit Institute of Arts, 1942-1970; (3 folders) (Box 3, Folder 9-11)
  - Detroit Urban League, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Drosser - Evans, 1894-1943 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Farquhar - Ford, 1901-1931 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Franklin Institute, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Ganapol - Graves, 1900-1919 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Hagedom - Hinchman, 1901-1919 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Grant Hildebrand, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Hirschman - E. K., 1901-1919 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Felix Kahn - Gus Kahn, 1900-1942 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Joseph and Rosalie Kahn, 1894-1903 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Julius Kahn, 1897-1920, undated; (5 folders) (Box 3, Folder 22-26)
  - Louis Kahn, 1902-1919 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Moritz Kahn, 1898-1901, undated; (4 folders) (Box 3, Folder 28-31)
  - Otto Kahn - Kaufmann, 1894-1931 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Koyl - MacDonald and Kahn Co., Ltd., 1894-1950 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Alexander Mackintosh, 1901 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - George D. Mason, 1894-1939, undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - McClintock - Michigan, 1900-1969 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Carl Milles, 1933-1942; (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 37-38)
  - Marioti - N. M. N., 1921, undated (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - National Industrial Service Bureau - Norris, 1900-1919 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Openhym - Park and Tilford, 1891-1919 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Pennsylvania, University of, 1943-1964 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Phillips Academy - Rubberoid Company, 1895-1943; (Oversized Material Housed in Box 6) (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Schulherr - Stevens, 1901-1942 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Arthur A. Stoughton, 1894-1904, undated (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Syracuse University, 1942-1943 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Alexander and Gertrude Trowbridge, 1896, undated (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - United Aircraft Corporation - Werthmann, 1901-1942 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Wiley Family, 1894-1902 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Winston - Zenner, 1893-1942 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Oversized Letter from the Rubberoid Company, 1943; (from Box 3, Folder 43) (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Personal Business Records, 1891-1943; Series 3; (Box 3; 7 folders)
  Personal business records include a power of attorney for Julius Kahn, records of stocks and income, lists of expenses and receipts for construction, property records, price lists for paintings by others, and miscellaneous receipts.
  - Power of Attorney for Julius Kahn, 1891 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Medical Receipts, 1900-1939, undated (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Records of Stocks and Income, 1902-1938 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Lists of Expenses and Receipts for Construction, 1897-1920, undated (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Property Records, 1916-1919, undated (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Price Lists for Paintings by Others, 1930, undated (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Miscellaneous Receipts, 1901-1943, undated (Box 3, Folder 57)
- Art Work, 1890-1936; Series 4; (Box 3, 6, OV 11-12; 20 folders)
  Art work consists of nine sketchbooks and drawings by Albert Kahn primarily depicting architectural details and notes. Art work by others includes a paper silhouette portrait of Kahn, drawings, watercolors, etchings, and lithographs primarily by Andrew F. Affleck, Samuel Chamberlain, and Hugh Ferriss. There is also a sketchbook of Cornwall by an unidentified artist.
  - Sketchbooks 1 and 2, undated (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Sketchbook 3, undated (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Sketchbook 4, undated (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Sketchbook 5, 1890-1891 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Sketchbook 6, 1891 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Sketchbook 7, 1908 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Sketchbook 8, 1911-1912 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Sketchbook 9, 1932-1936 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Drawings by Albert Kahn, 1891-1933, undated; (3 folders) (Box 3, Folder 66-68)
  - Silhouette Cut-Out of Albert Kahn, undated (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Etchings by Others, undated (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Drawings by Samuel Chamberlain, undated (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Watercolors by Samuel Chamberlain, undated (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Lithographs by Samuel Chamberlain, undated; (Oversized Material Housed in OV 11) (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Sketchbook of Cornwall by an Unidentified Artist, 1892 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Three Oversized Etchings by Andrew F. Affleck, undated; (from Box 3, Folder 70) (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Oversized Book of Lithographs Vingt Lithographies du Vieux Paris par Samuel Chamberlain, undated; (from Box 3, Folder 73) (Box OV 11)
  - Oversized Etching by Andrew F. Affleck, undated; (from Box 3, Folder 70) (Box OV 12)
  - Oversized Charcoal Drawing of the General Motors Building by Hugh Ferriss, 1919 (Box OV 12)
- Notes and Writings, 1899-1943; Series 5; (Box 3-4; 29 folders)
  Notes and writings include Ernestine Kahn's diary containing sporadic and brief entries including miscellaneous notes and computations of figures, notebooks containing brief annotations, guest registers and records concerning Albert Kahn's funeral, an inventory of Kahn's library, and typescripts of speeches and lectures concerning city development, labor conditions, and miscellaneous architectural topics.
  - Ernestine Kahn's Diary, 1899 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Notebooks 1 and 2, undated (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Notebooks 3 and 4, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Notebook 5, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Notebook 6, 1909 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Guest Register, 1929-1944 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Funeral Guest Register, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Record of Remembrances about Albert Kahn, 1942; (3 folders) (Box 4, Folder 6-8)
  - Register of Telephone Calls Following the Death of Albert Kahn, 1942-1943 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Inventory of Kahn's Library, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Notes: "Things Albert Kahn Found Amusing,", undated; (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 11-12)
  - Manuscript for a Speech, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Typescript for a Speech, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Typescript of Speech "Problems in City Development,", undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Typescript "Improvements in Labor Conditions,", undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Manuscript for Lecture on Renaissance Architecture, 1900; (4 folders) (Box 4, Folder 17-20)
  - Manuscript for Dedication Speech at Magnus Butzel Library, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Lecture Notes at Wednesday Night Club, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Typescript for Lecture in Tribute to George D. Mason on the Dedicaton of Masonic Temple Building, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Typescript "The Farce of Modern Art" by an Unidentified Author, undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Typescript "The Industrial Aesthetic of Albert Kahn,", undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Typescript "A Tribute to Albert Kahn" by Dr. Leo M. Franklin, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous Notes and Writings, 1901-1927, undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Scrapbooks, 1890-1942; Series 6; (Box 7; 0.3 linear feet)
  Scrapbook 1 contains clippings, small drawings, and photographs including cyanotypes of architecture. Scrapbook 2 contains letters of tribute to Kahn from his business colleagues.
  - Oversized Scrapbook 1, 1890-1897 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Scrapbook 2, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Printed Material, 1897-1968; Series 7; (Box 4-6, OV 10; 0.8 linear feet)
  Printed material includes clippings, exhibition catalogs for others, programs, booklets, books including Albert Kahn Organization containing autographs of Kahn's business colleagues, and Shooting the Russian War autographed by its author, Margaret Bourke-White. Picture postcards are of the Detroit Golf Club and the Brooklyn Y.M.C.A. both designed by Kahn, and of various scenic places of interest in the United States and Europe. There are also reproductions of art work, brochures, phonograph record catalogs, blueprints of designs for cups and saucers by Kahn's daughter Lydia Winston, and miscellaneous printed material.
  - Clippings, undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Clippings, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Clippings, 1939-1963 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Exhibition Catalogs for Others, 1926, undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Programs, 1897-1942; (12 folders) (Box 4, Folder 32-43)
  - Booklet Practical Calculation and Application of Reinforced Concrete, undated (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Booklet General Motors Building (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Booklet Eight Murals at the Michigan Exhibit, Century of Progress Exposition, Chicago, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Booklet Albert Kahn at the Ford Exposition Building, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Booklet Memoirs of Mollie Kahn Fuchs with Poster, 1940-1968; (Oversized Material Housed in Box 6) (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Book The American Historian's Raw Materials by J. Franklin Jameson, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Book Albert Kahn Organization, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Book Shooting the Russian War by Margaret Bourke-White, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Book Builders for Battle by David O. Woodbury, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Book The Story of Ambitious Men by Edward Geller, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Reproductions of Art Work, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Travel Brochures for Germany, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Travel Brochures for Amalfi, Italy, 1909 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Phonograph Record Catalogs, 1931, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Brochures, 1970, undated; (Oversized Material Housed in OV 10) (Box 5, Folder 6-7)
  - Picture Postcards: Detroit Golf Club Designed by Kahn, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Picture Postcards: Y.M.C.A., Brooklyn, New York, Designed by Kahn, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Picture Postcards: California, District of Columbia, Illinois, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Picture Postcards: Massachusetts, undated; (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 11-12)
  - Picture Postcards: Missouri, Nebraska, New Hampshire, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Picture Postcards: New York, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Picture Postcards: Ohio, Pennsylvania, Virginia, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Picture Postcards: France and Spain, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Picture Postcards: Scotland and England, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Souvenir Tickets to Miscellaneous Events, 1934-1942, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1900-1947, undated; (3 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 6 and OV 10) (Box 5, Folder 19-21)
  - Oversized Poster Concerning Mollie Kahn Fuchs's Development of the Multi-Color Printing Process for Blueprints, 1968; (from Box 4, Folder 48) (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Two Oversized Menus from Café Metropole in Russian, German, and English, undated; (from Box 5, Folder 21) (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Oversized Brochure for Reproductions of Art Work, undated; (from Box 5, Folder 6) (Box OV 10)
  - Oversized Poster Advertising Newspaper Article "Million Dollar Office Boy: The Story of Albert Kahn,", undated; (from Box 5, Folder 20) (Box OV 10)
  - Oversized Blueprints of Designs for Cups and Saucers by Kahn's Daughter, Lydia Winston, 1947; (from Box 5, Folder 20) (Box OV 10)
- Photographs, 1875-1944; Series 8; (Box 5-6, 8, MGP 2; 1.0 linear feet)
  Photographs are of Albert Kahn, his wife Ernestine including two by Clara E. Sipprell, members of the Kahn family, and colleagues including Myron Barlow, Frida Kahlo, Diego Rivera, Arturo Toscanini, residences including an album of photographs of the Edsel Ford House designed by Kahn, travel photographs taken by Kahn in Algiers, France, Germany, Italy, Spain, a photograph album "Our Trip to Utica, and photographs of art work. There are also five reels of 16mm motion picture film of the Kahn family at the farm and at various family gatherings. Glass plate negative housed separately and closed to researchers.